BU Records: Delta Theta Phi, Inclusive: 1948-1968, undated, Bulk: 1955-1958, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: Delta Theta Phi
Inclusive: 1948-1968, undated, Bulk: 1955-1958, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/82
Delta Theta Phi, 1913 -
2 document boxes
BU Records: Delta Theta Phi contains a variety of materials related to the Baylor University chapter of the law fraternity. These include correspondence, accounting and banking records, information about members and organization traditions, and organization publications.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
Delta Theta Phi is an international academic fraternity for law students. It was founded in Chicago in 1913 through the unification of three earlier organizations, the Delta Phi Delta, Alpha Kappa Phi, and Theta Lambda Phi law fraternities. At the time of unification, Delta Theta Phi had 32 chapters, or “senates”, across the nation. The organization continued to expand internationally when two senates were established in Puerto Rico in 1969. The organization admitted its first female member in 1971. Delta Theta Phi also obtained its own law review, the Adelphia Law Journal, after it merged with Sigma Nu Phi law fraternity in 1989. The Baylor University chapter of Delta Theta Phi, known as the James P. Alexander Senate, was established in 1949.
Scope and Content
BU Records: Delta Theta Phi consists of materials from 1948-1968, with some undated items. The materials reflect the activities of the James P. Alexander Senate, the Baylor University branch of the law fraternity.
This collection is arranged into four series. Series I. Correspondence contains the letters sent and received by members of the organization, with the majority of them being to the national headquarters of the fraternity. Series II. Financial Records contains the records related to members dues. Series III. Organization Records contains the constitution, by-laws, and information about events hosted by the fraternity. Series IV. Literary Productions contains club manuals and journals published by the national organization.
Arrangement
Prior to processing, this collection was housed in labeled and unlabeled folders with no apparent arrangement. Some folders were arranged by topic. For this current round of processing, some materials of the same topic were group together.
There are four series within this collection, I. Correspondence, II. Organization Records, III. Financial Records, IV. Literary Productions.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/82.
Related Resources
Related references
BU Records: Delta Theta Phi, Accession #BU/82, Box 1, Folder 3, The Texas Collection, Baylor University.
“History - Delta Theta Phi.” Delta Theta Phi, Law Fraternity International. Delta Theta Phi. Accessed 2019 October 9.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University. Law School.; Delta Theta Phi Law Fraternity.; Delta Theta Phi
Subjects
Financial records.; Handbooks and manuals.; Law students -- Societies, etc.; Periodicals.
Genres
Correspondence.; Informational works.
- Correspondence, 1955-1958, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Good.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains of the Delta Theta Phi fraternity. The condition of the series is good.
  - Letters Dispatched, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Letters Recieved, 1955-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Organization Records, 1955-1958, undated; 2
  This series contains the fraternity constitutions and by-laws, membership rolls, and information about organization event. The condition of the series is good.
  - Fraternity Constitution and By-Laws, 1955-1957, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Membership, 1955-1958 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Organization Events, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Financial Records, 1955-1958, undated; 3
  This series contains the banking statements and accounting books. The condition of the series is good.
  - Financial Records, 1955-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Accounting Books, 1955-1958, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Literary Productions, 1948-1968, undated; 4
  This series contains the organizational manuals regarding fraternity traditions and copies of two publications, the "Student Lawyer Journal" and the "Paper Book", the official Delta Theta Phi publication. The condition of the series is good.
  - Delta Theta Phi Manuels, 1948-1957, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - “The Student Lawyer Journal”, 1956 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - “The Paper Book”, 1956-1958 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - “The Paper Book”, 1959-1960 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - “The Paper Book”, 1961-1962 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - “The Paper Book”, 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - “The Paper Book”, 1966-1968 (Box 2, Folder 7)